Scott Harvey

Senior Full Stack Software Developer Specializing in JavaScript and ColdFusion (202) 744-5379 | scott.harvey@outlook.com | https://portfolio.scottharvey.dev

SUMMARY

Software developer with over fifteen years of experience building, maintaining, and enhancing applications that improve and automate business processes for organizations including the U.S. Air Force, Environmental Protection Agency, National Institutes of Health, and the Association of American Medical Colleges.

- Eligible for Security Clearance
- Adobe Certified Expert in ColdFusion

FULL STACK and OTHER SKILLS

Back-End: MS SQL Server | MySQL | Oracle | MongoDB

Middleware: ColdFusion | PHP | Node (Express)

Front-End: JavaScript: Vanilla, jQuery, React (Next), JSX, Node (Express) | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | XML

Tools: Management: Jira | Confluence | Slack | Trello | HubSpot CMS | Splunk

DevOps: GitHub | Subversion | TortoiseSVN | Bamboo

IDEs: Visual Studio Code | Brackets

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer 2019 — present

Providing on-site and off-site database and web development support for client projects.

JavaScript (Vanilla / NuxtJS (NextJS / VueJS)) | HTML | CSS | HubSpot CMS | MS SQL Server

- **Autonomy:** Developing and maintaining responsive front-end web pages, mobile application screens, and marketing emails using VueJS, NuxtJS, HTML, and CSS.
- **agencyQ**: Developing responsive front-end JavaScript, HTML, and CSS modules in HubSpotCMS, including featured blog posts, client testimonials, an image rotator that retrieves its data by querying the HubDB database, and more.
- **Noble Technologies, Inc.:** Performing routine data management tasks using MS SQL, including database backups, data loads, data validation, and report writing. Assisting with database design and modeling, stored procedure writing, and interface support.

Association of American Medical Colleges (AAMC)

2016 - 2018

Senior Software Engineer

Developing and maintaining survey and reporting tools serving association members, including medical schools, students, and faculty.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | ColdFusion | Oracle

Providing software design, coding, testing, implementation, documentation, and maintenance on a team of 2 developers, a business analyst, a quality assurance specialist, and a project manager. Performing data analysis, research, and ad hoc reporting according to client needs.

Solution Technology Systems, Inc. (STSI)

2015 - 2016

Developing and maintaining Personal Security System, an automated workflow application that initiates, tracks, and manages background investigations for all Environmental Protection Agency personnel.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | ColdFusion | Oracle

- Providing software coding, testing, implementation, documentation, and maintenance.
- Analyzing, coding, testing, and deploying 40+ change requests to production code, using CMMI processes.
- Identifying business and technical solutions to enable the EPA to optimize business performance.

Council for Logistics Research (CLR)

2003 - 2014

Senior Web Developer

Developing and maintaining software for CLR and its clients including the US Air Force. Managing and mentoring junior developers in a small team. Establishing and maintaining best practices and coding standards for the team.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | ColdFusion | MS SQL Server

Translating business needs into functional requirements and specifications in development of *The Eye*, a robust browser-based enterprise resource planning (ERP) application. Accomplishments include:

- Automating processes including expense reports, purchase orders, purchase requisitions, performance reviews, training requests, time entry and attendance, while adhering to DCAA regulations.
- Consolidating multiple data sources into a single, secure repository for streamlined reporting.

Designing, developing, and implementing software applications for the U.S. Air Force and other clients, such as:

- Enterprise resource planning (ERP) software including resume and skill set tracking
- Event registration and evaluation software
- Content management software, including role-based security, maintenance, and search

agencyQ

Freelance Web Developer

2006 - 2013

Developing and maintaining software for clients of the company.

JavaScript | HTML | ColdFusion | Oracle

- National Institutes of Health (NIH), 2009 2013: Maintaining and developing new functionality for the National Institute on Drug Abuse division's report-creation tool Jennica.
- Best Cellars, 2007: Completing an e-commerce migration.

Other Positions

- Web Application Developer, Capital Markets Technology Inc., 2002-2003
- Web Developer, Q Industries, 1999-2002

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Full Stack Web Developer Certificate, Hyperion Dev, 2019 2020
- Adobe ColdFusion Developer Week, 2020
- Amazon Web Services Public Sector Summits, 2020 and 2018
- Certified Expert in ColdFusion, Adobe, 2008
- Hands-On IT Project Management, Project Management Institute, 2005

EDUCATION

- Intro to Graphic Design, Corcoran College of Art and Design, 2007
- Carnegie Mellon University, Mellon College of Sciences, 1992 1995